-Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Penguin sighting! Man or myth?
见到企鹅了!是人还是谜?
What is he? Today's edition. Another penguin sighting.
他是什么? 今天专题-- 又见到企鹅了
Another penguin sighting! Check it out!
又见到企鹅了!先睹为快!
Penguin man living in Gotham's sewers! Read all about the latest sighting!
怪异企鹅人住在加森下水道中! 快来看最新目击报导!
May I have your attention, Gotham City?
请注意,加森市
It is time for tonight's lighting of the tree.
今晚点燃圣诞树的时刻已经到了
How about that?
好看吧?
Part man, part penguin! All horrifying!
半人半企鹅!十分恐怖!
Find out for only 50 cents! Come on!
来喔!只要50分钱便能得知真相!
Read about the possible terror beneath our feet! Check it out!
快看看存在于我们脚下的可能危险! 快来看,各位!
Read about it!
快来看今天的报导! 看看最新的企鹅怪物目击报导
Missing link between man and bird.
喂,这是人与鸟间的缺失环节
My dear boy...
孩子...
...sometimes it's a diversion to read such rubbish.
...有时看那种垃圾是种消遣
Usually, it's a waste of time.
但多数时候是浪费时间
Whatever. Today's issue! '"The Penguin: Man or myth?'"
随你说 今日专题! "企鹅:是人还是谜?"
The Globe! Right here! 25 cents!
环球报! 在此! 25分钱!
Well, here's hoping.
唔,这里是有希望的
With luck, Gotham will have its first merry Christmas in years.
带点幸运的话 加森市可以在几年后过第一个圣诞节
I feel almost vulgar at Yuletide...
我觉得很粗俗,在圣诞季节...
...mentioning the new power plant.
...提起新发电厂
But if we're to break ground when we must, I'll need permits...
但我们若要动工兴建 就需要许可...
...variances, tax incentives. That sort of pesky nonsense.
...法规变通、减税鼓励 那类讨厌的枝微末节
Power plant?
发电厂?
Studies show we've enough power to get us into the middle of the next century.
麦斯,所有研究均显示 我们的电力足以应付到下世纪中期
Your analysts foresee growth at 1 % per annum. That's a mild swelling.
你的分析家指的是每年1%的人口成长 那不是成长,是温和膨胀
Imagine...
试想像...
...a Gotham City...
...一个加森市...
...of the future, lit up like a blanket of stars...
...在未来,灯光燃起如一片繁星...
...but blinking on and off...
...但却闪灭不定...
...embarrassingly low on juice.
...电力低得令人难堪
Frankly...
老实说...
...I cringe, Mr. Mayor.
...我因而畏缩,市长先生
Sorry, any plans must go to the usual committees...
抱歉,你的任何计划都得循正常管道...
...through the usual channels.
...向负责委员会申请
I have a suggestion.
我有个建议
Well...
好的...
...actually, really, just more like a question.
...事实上,更像是个问题
I'm afraid we haven't properly housebroken Ms. Kyle.
恐怕我们未适当训练凯尔小姐
In the plus column, though...
但她有个优点...
...she makes great coffee.
...她泡的咖啡非常香
Dad.
爸
Mr. Mayor. Time to go down and bring joy to the masses.
市长先生,该下去为大众带来喜悦了
'"Actually, more of a question.'"
"事实上,更是个问题"
You stupid corn dog.
你是愚蠢的笨狗
Corn dog, corn dog.
笨狗, 笨狗
I have enough signatures from Shreck employees to warrant a recall.
我光靠许瑞克的员工 便可以取得重选的签名
That's not a threat, just simple numbers.
那不是威胁,只是单纯的数据
Maybe. But you sure as hell don't have an issue or a candidate.
也许 但你没有立场,也没有候选人
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
非常感谢各位女士、先生
From those of us at City Hall to each and every one of you...
祝我们市政府的人和你们所有的人...
...happy holidays.
...假期快乐
We have with us a man who needs no introduction, he's given us so much.
今晚有位不需要多作介绍的人 与我们同在,他对本市贡献良多
Please welcome Gotham's own Santa Claus, Max Shreck.
请欢迎加森市的圣诞老人--麦斯.许瑞克
Pick up those contracts for Personnel and...
到人事处拿那些合约...
...pick up the dry cleaning and paper towels....
...再去拿干洗衣物和纸巾...
Darn!
糟糕!
I forgot my speech.
我忘了我的演讲稿
Remind me to take it out on what's-her-name.
提醒我教训那个叫什么的
Santa Claus?
圣诞老人?
Afraid not.
恐怕不是
I'm just a poor schmo. Got lucky.
我只是个低贱的走运笨蛋
Sue me...
我要回馈你们...
...if I want to give some back.
...若不满意,就告我吧
I only wish I could hand out more than just...
但愿我能送出的,不只是...
...expensive baubles.
...昂贵的玩具
I wish I could hand out world peace...
但愿我能送出世界和平...
...and unconditional love...
...和无条件的爱...
...wrapped in a big bow.
...包在大蝴蝶结(礼盒)中
Oh, but you can.
但是你可以
Oh, but you will.
你会的
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Great idea.
好主意
Not mine.
不是我的主意
What are you waiting for? The signal!
你在等什么?发出讯号!
We want the big guy! The guy who runs the show!
我们要大角色! 主导一切的那个家伙!
What do you want?
你要什么?
Not you!
不是你!
Shreck!
许瑞克!
You'll have to go through me.
你得先过我这一关
Dad, go! Save yourself!
奇普 爸,快走!救你自己!
Dad, go!
爸,快走!
Shut up!
闭嘴!
Take one step closer, Mr. Manbat, and I'll--
蝙蝠人先生,你要是再上前一步,我就--
You missed.
没打中
The Batman.
哇!是蝙蝠侠
Or is it just '"Batman'"?
或只是"蝙蝠人"?
Your choice, of course.
当然,任你选择
Well, that was...
这真是...
...very brief.
...非常短暂
Just like all the men in my life.
就和我生命中的所有男人一样
What men?
什么男人?
Well...
但是...
...then again, there's you. But you need therapy.
...话说回来,还有你 不过你需要治疗
Thanks for saving the day, Batman. The Circus Gang is back.
谢谢你拯救我们,蝙蝠侠 恐怕马戏团帮又回来了
We'll see.
静观其后吧
They almost made off with our mover and shaker, Max Shreck.
他们差点抓走麦斯.许瑞克
Where is that insufferable son of a bitch?
那令人难以忍受的混蛋呢?
I believe the word you're looking for is....
相信你搜寻的字眼是... 啊--!
Actually, this is all just a bad dream.
事实上,这一切只是个恶梦
You're at home in bed...
你在家中床上...
...heavily sedated, resting comfortably...
...无比宁静,安适地休息着...
...dying from the carcinogens you've personally spewed...
...口吐致癌物而垂将等死...
...in a lifetime of profiteering.
...只因你毕生牟取暴利
Tragic irony...
是悲剧性的讽刺...
...or poetic justice?
...或诗歌般的正义?
You tell me.
你告诉我
My God, it's true.
天啊,是真的
Penguin Man of the sewer.
下水道的企鹅人
Odd as it may seem, Max...
奇怪的是,麦斯...
...you and I have something in common:
...你和我有些共通之处
We're both perceived as monsters.
我们都被视同怪物一般
But somehow...
然而...
...you're a well-respected monster...
...你是个倍受尊敬的怪物...
...and I am, to date...
...而我则...
...not!
...不然!
Frankly, I feel that's a bum rap. I'm a businessman.
老实说,我不以为然 我是个生意人
Tough, yes.
强硬,对
Shrewd, okay. But that does not make me a monster.
刻薄,也行 但还不足使我成为怪物
Don't embarrass yourself, Max!
别糗自己了,麦斯!
I know all about you.
我对你一清二楚
What you hide, I discover.
你隐藏,我发掘
What you put in your toilet...
你弃于马桶中的...
...I place on my mantle. Get the picture?
...我将它保存起来,明白吗?
Is that supposed to hypnotize me?
那是什么? 打算对我催眠吗?
No, just give you a splitting headache.
不,只是要让你头痛欲裂
It's not working.
没有效
Oh, you big baby!
喔,大男孩!
Just blanks.
只是空炮弹
Would I go through all this trouble just to kill you?
今晚我大费周章,只为杀你吗?
No, Max.
不,麦斯
I have an entirely other purpose.
我有个全然不同的目的
I'm ready, Max.
我准备好了,麦斯
I've been down here too long.
我已在下面太久
It's time for me to ascend...
我该上升了...
...to re-emerge...
...重新出现...
...with your help...
...借着你的帮助...
...your know-how...
...你的深谙此道...
...your savvy.
...你的机伶
I wasn't born in the sewer, you know.
我并非生于下水道
I come from...
我来自...
...Iike you.
...和你一样
And, like you, I want some respect!
而且和你一样,我要受到尊重!
A recognition of my basic humanity.
得到我的基本人权
But most of all...
但最重要的...
...I want to find out who I am...
...我要藉找到我父母...
...by finding my parents...
...来查出我是谁...
...Iearning my human name.
...得知我的姓名
Simple stuff that the good people of Gotham take for granted!
加森人视为当然的简单事情!
And...
那...
...exactly why am I going to help you?
...我到底为何要帮你?
Well....
好的...
Let's start.
我们开始吧
Let's see what we have in here.
让我看看这里有些什么
A batch of toxic waste...
一些有毒的废水...
...from your clean textile plant!
...取自你干净的纺织厂!
There's a whole lagoon of this crud in the back!
这种废物,后面有一大池!
It could have come from anywhere.
那可能来自任何地方
What about the documents that prove you own half of the firetraps in Gotham City?
证明你拥有加森市 半数易燃建筑的文件呢?
If there were such documents...
若有那种文件...
...that's not an admission...
...而且我不允许有...
...they would've been shredded.
...它们早就被切碎了
Good idea.
好主意
A lot of tape and a little patience make all the difference.
许多胶带和一点耐心 情况便截然不同
By the way...
对了...
...how's Fred Atkins, your old partner?
...你的老合伙人--佛列德.亚特金好吗?
Fred?
佛列德?
Fred's actually....
事实上,佛列德他...
I believe he's on an extended vacation. He's good.
我相信他正在度延长假期 他很好
Good.
很好
Hiya, Max. Remember me? I'm Fred's hand!
你好,麦斯,记得我吗? 我是佛列德的手!
Want to greet any other body parts?
要向其它部份的肢体致意吗?
Remember, Max...
记住,麦斯...
...you flush it, I flaunt it.
...你摒弃的,我珍惜
You know what, Mr. Penguin, sir?
你知道吗,企鹅先生?
I think, perhaps...
我想,或许...
...I could help orchestrate a '"Welcome Home'" scenario for you.
...我能协助你策划一个欢迎返乡的策略
Once we're both back home, perhaps we could help each other.
等我们俩都回到家 或许我们能互相帮助
You won't regret this, Mr. Shreck.
你不会后悔的,许瑞克先生
Honey, I'm home!
亲爱的,我回来了!
Oh, I forgot. I'm not married.
噢,我忘了,我未婚
Miss Kitty.
猫咪小姐
Back from more sexual escapades you refuse to share?
从拒绝分享的性胡闹活动归来了吗?
Not that I'd ever pry.
不是我爱刺探
Drink your dinner.
喝的晚餐吧
What?
怎么了?
How can anyone be so pathetic?
怎么会有人如此可悲?
Yes, to you I seem pathetic, but I'm a working girl.
对,对而言,我是可悲 但我是个上班女郎
Must pay the rent. Maybe if you chipped in instead of stepping out.
得付房租 若能贡献点生活费,而不要开溜就好了
Selina, dear, it's your mother. Just calling to say hello.
瑟琳娜,亲爱的,是妈 只是打电话问候一下
Yeah, but....
对,但是...
But I'm disappointed you're not coming home for Christmas.
但是我很失望,不回家过圣诞节
I want to discuss why you insist on languishing in Gotham City...
我要和讨论 为何坚持要在加森市受折磨...
...as some lowly secretary.
...像一些低级秘书一样
Lowly assistant.
是低级助理
Selina, about that Christmas getaway we planned....
瑟琳娜,记得我们的圣诞出游计划吗?...
I'll be going alone. Dr. Shaw says I need to be my own person, not an appendage.
我将要独自去 萧博士说我需要独处,而非附属品
Some appendage!
真是个附属品!
The party never stops on Selina Kyle's answering machine.
瑟琳娜.凯尔的录音机盛宴永不停息
I should've let him win that last racquetball game.
看来上次打板球时,我该让他赢的
Hello...
哈...
...Selina Kyle.
...瑟琳娜.凯尔
We're calling to tell you about exciting, new Gotham Lady perfume.
我们要告诉有种新的加森女士香水
It makes women feel like women... and the men have no complaints either.
它会使女人感觉像女人... 而且男人不会有抱怨
This is yourself reminding you to come all the way back to the office...
嗨,瑟琳娜,这是提醒自己　真蠢! 得回办公室去...
-...if you forgot the Bruce Wayne file.... -You stupid corn dog!
...如果忘记带布鲁斯.韦恩的档案回来... 你这个笨蛋!　...星期三有个会议
Working late?
加班吗?
I'm just boning up for your Bruce Wayne meeting in the morning.
我只是在帮你预备明早 和布鲁斯.韦恩开会的资料
I pulled all the files on the proposed power plant...
我调出发电厂企划案的所有档案...
...and Mr. Wayne's hoped-for investment. I even opened the protected files--
...还有预备请韦恩先生投资的文件 我甚至打开了保护档--
How industrious!
多勤奋啊!
How did you open the protected files?
是如何打开保护档的?
May I ask?
我能问吗?
I figured your password was '"Geraldo,'" your Chihuahua, and it was.
我想你的密码是"Geraldo" 是你吉娃娃的名字
This is all very interesting, though a bit on the technical side...
这实在非常有趣 虽然在技术上有一点难懂...
...about how the power plant is a power plant in name only...
...我是指发电厂 如何只在名义上是发电厂...
...since, in fact, it's going to be a big, giant...
...而事实上,它将是个大的...
...big, giant...capacitor.
...巨大的...容电器
And, instead of generating power, it'll be sucking power from...
它不会产生电力,反而会吸收...
...Gotham City...
...加森市的电力...
...and storing it...
...并且贮存起来...
...stockpiling it...
...囤积它...
...which is a very novel approach, I'd say.
...我得说那是个非常新奇的方式
Who'd you say this to?
有将此事告诉谁?
Nobody.
没告诉别人
What did curiosity do to the cat?
好奇会使猫如何呢?
I'm no cat.
我不是猫
I'm just an assistant.
我只是个助理
A secretary.
是个秘书
And a very good one.
而且是非常好的一个
Too good?
太好了?
Listen...
听着...
...it's our secret. Honest.
...那是我们的秘密,真的
How can you be so mean to someone so meaningless?
你怎能对一个无意义的人如此残忍?
This power plant...
这发电厂...
...is my legacy. It's what I leave behind.
...将是我的传家宝,是我遗留下来的
For Chip.
留给奇普
Nothing must prevent that.
任何事都无法阻止
Go ahead. Intimidate me. Bully me, if it makes you feel big.
好,动手吧 恐吓我,欺压我,若能使你觉得强大
It's not like you can kill me!
反正你又不可能杀了我!
Actually, it's a lot like that.
事实上,很有可能
For a second, you really frightened me.
有那么一会,你真的吓到我了
Really?
真是的
Honey, I'm home!
亲爱的,我回来了!
Oh, I forgot. I'm not married.
噢,我忘了,我未婚
Selina, this is your mother. Call me.
瑟琳娜,我是妈,打电话给我
Selina, this is your mother. Why haven't you called me back?
瑟琳娜,我是妈 为何没回我电话?
Hello, Selina Kyle.
哈,瑟琳娜.凯尔
We're just calling to make sure you've tried Gotham Lady perfume.
我们打电话 是想确定已试用过加森女士香水
One whiff of this and your boss will ask you to stay after work...
在办公室只要喷一下 你老板会要下班后留下...
...for a candlelight staff meeting for two.
...开二人烛光员工会议
Gotham Lady perfume. Exclusively at Shreck's department store.
加森女士香水 许瑞克百货公司仅售
I don't know about you, Miss Kitty, but I feel...
我不知道觉得如何,猫咪小姐 但我觉得...
...so much yummier.
...真是棒透了
Ladies and gentlemen:
女士、先生们
I stand before you again to denounce the urban chaos we live with in our city.
我再度在你们面前 谴责与我们共存于这城市的紊乱
It's got to stop.
它得停止
It's going to stop! Our community is coming apart...
它将停止! 在这应该聚合的时节...
...in a season when it should be coming together.
...我们的社区正崩离
I don't care what the cynics may say. This is the Christmas season...
我不在乎批评者会怎么说 现在是圣诞时节...
...and should be a healing time.
...应该是愈合的时候
I say that not only as an official...
我不只以官员的身份声明...
...but as a husband and a father.
...更以丈夫与父亲的立场说
Last night's violence won't happen again.
昨晚的暴行不会再发生
I'm not good at speeches, so I'll just say, "'Thanks. "'
我不擅于言词 因此我只能说"谢了"
It's the hideous Penguin Man.
天啊,是可怕的企鹅人
Take the baby. Just don't hurt me, please!
孩子你带走,但请别伤害我!
This was the remarkable scene only minutes ago in Gotham Plaza.
这是数分钟前在加森广场 发生的非凡情况
The mysterious Penguin saving the life of the mayor's baby...
神秘的企鹅解救市长之子...
-...and announcing his presence. -All I want in return...
...并宣布他的存在 我要的回报...
...is a chance...
...是想找回...
...to find my mom and dad.
...找出我的父母
A chance to find out who they are...
一个查出他们是谁...
...and thusly...
...进而知道...
...who I am.
...我是谁的机会
And then...
然后...
...with my parents...
...从我父母那儿...
...try to understand...why.
...设法了解,为什么...
Why they did what I guess they felt they had to do...
为何他们做出他们觉得非做不可的事...
...to a child...
...对一个孩子...
...who was born...
...一个生来...
...a little different.
...有点不同的
A child...
孩子...
...who spent his first Christmas...
...让他度过第一个圣诞节...
...and many since...
...和之后许多个...
...in a sewer.
...都在下水道中
Mr. Wayne? Something wrong?
韦恩先生?有何不对吗? 没有
His parents.
他的父母
This scene, direct from Gotham Plaza.
再度说明,本画面直接拍自加森广场
I hope he finds them.
但愿他找到他们
Here he is, standing alongside Gotham's leading citizen, Max Shreck.
他正站在加森市模范市民-- 麦斯.许瑞克的旁边
How about a statement? People want to know.
说句话好吗? 市民们想知道
-Penguin's not to be disturbed! -It's a public place!
企鹅人不该被打扰的! 这是公共场所!
-Walk. Now. Move. -Freedom of the press!
走开,现在,快走开 新闻舆论的自由!
Wait a minute.
等一下
What about the freedom to rediscover your roots...
是什么样的想法,让你想寻找你的根...
...with dignity and privacy?
...掺杂尊严和隐私?
Is the Penguin a personal friend?
企鹅是你私人的朋友?
He's a personal friend of the whole city, so have a heart.
他是整个城市的私人朋友 只要有着一颗心
Give the Constitution a rest. It's Christmas.
让法规休息一下 这是圣诞节
'"Red Triangle Circus put on a swell show with fierce lions.
"红三角马戏团表演声势浩大 还有凶猛的狮子"
'"Circus returns for a two-week....
"马戏团表演将为期两周..."
'"Kids will love....'"
"小孩会喜欢的...."
Thanks.
谢谢
It's cold!
好冷!
It's vichyssoise.
这是掺有马铃薯的奶油汤
It's supposed to be cold.
冷了才好喝
'"Circus is back with a freak show, may not be suitable for kids...
"马戏团回来,又带着怪异的表演 并不适合小孩..."
'"...featuring a poodle lady...
"...特写一位狮子头女士..."
'"...the world's fattest man...
"...世界最胖的人..."
'"...and Aquatic Bird Boy.'"
"...水上鸟男孩"
Why are you determined to prove...
你为何决心证明...
...that this Penguin is not what he seems?
...这个企鹅人所言不实?
Must you be the only lonely '"man-beast'" in town?
你一定得当全城唯一的"人兽"吗?
'"The circus folded its tents yesterday...
"马戏团昨天收起帐篷..."
'"...after reports of missing children in several towns.
"...在数个城镇发生无数儿童失踪案件后"
'"Police have closed down the Red Triangle fairgrounds.
"警方已关闭红三角表演场"
'"However, at least one freak-show performer vanished before...
"然而,至少有一名畸型表演者..."
'"...he could be questioned.'"
"...在接受侦讯前失踪了"
I suppose you feel better now.
我想你觉得好多了,主人
No.
没有
Actually, I feel worse.
事实上,我觉得更糟
Why're you still out?
你为何还在外面?
Are you concerned about that strange, heroic Penguin person?
你是在关心那个英雄般怪异的企鹅人吗?
I think he knows who his parents are.
我想他知道他父母是谁
There's something else.
他另有所图
Mr. Penguin....
企鹅先生...
A penguin is a bird that cannot fly!
企鹅是鸟类却不会飞!
I am a man!
我是个人!
I have a name!
我有名字!
Oswald Cobblepot!
奥兹瓦.卡伯波特!
You'll never be able to settle with them?
你从未和他们生活在一起?
True.
是的
I was their "Number-One"" son...
我是他们"第一流"的儿子
...and they treated me like number two.
...而他们待我却像二流的
But it's human nature to fear...
但人类的天性是害怕...
...the unusual.
...奇特的
Perhaps...
或许...
...when I held my...
...当我拿着...
...Tiffany baby rattle...
...小孩玩的拨浪鼓...
...with a shiny flipper...
...以带有光泽的蹼状手...
...instead of five chubby digits...
...而非五只圆胖的手指...
...they freaked.
...他们吓到了
But I forgive them.
但我原谅他们
'"Penguin forgives parents! 'I'm at peace with myself and the world!
"企鹅人原谅父母了!" "我对自己与世界都感到平和!"
'"'Don't need hands as long as you got heart.
"只要有心,便不需要手"
'"'My heart is filled with love. I feel five feet tall.""
"我的心充满爱,我觉得有五崭"
-He's like a frog that became a prince. -No, he's more like a penguin.
他像只变成王子的青蛙 不,他更像只企鹅
Now, now, pretty little thing.
好了,漂亮的小姑娘
Nice and easy.
乖乖听话
I love a big, strong man who's not afraid to show it with someone half his size.
我喜欢高大强壮,而且 勇于展现力量对付体型小他一半的人
Be gentle, it's my first time.
温柔点,这是我的第一次
Tic-tac-toe.
踢-踏-拳
You make it easy, don't you?
谢谢,我... 使自己容易受害,是吗?
Always waiting for some Batman to save you.
总是等着蝙蝠侠来救
I am Catwoman...
我是猫女...
...hear me roar.
...听我怒吼
I'd offer you coffee, but my assistant is using her vacation time.
我想请你喝咖啡 但我的助理正在休假
Good time. Everyone but the bandits'll be slacking off till after the New Year.
好时机,反正过年之前 除了盗贼以外,大家都想放松点
I'm not sure I like the inference.
我不确定是否喜欢你的推论,布鲁斯
I didn't realize I made one.
抱歉,麦斯 我不觉得我有做推论
I'm pushing this power plant now because it'll cost more later.
我现在促销发电厂计划 因为将来花费会更高
A million saved is a million earned.
省一百万等于赚一百万
I commissioned this report. Take a look at it.
我做了一份报告 也许你想看看
Gotham City has a power surplus. I'm sure you know that.
麦斯,重点是加森市已供电过量 我确信你知道
My question is:
我的问题是...
What's your angle?
你的目的为何?
'"Power surplus?'" Bruce, shame on you!
"供电过量?" 布鲁斯,你该惭愧!
No such thing. One can never have too much power.
没那回事 电力再多都不为过
If my life has a meaning, that's the meaning.
我的生命若有何意义,那就是意义
I'll fight you. I've already spoken to the mayor and we agree.
我将与你唱反调 我已和市长谈过,我们看法一致
Mayors come and go.
市长多如过江之鲫
Blue bloods tire easily.
贵族容易没落
Can you go 15 rounds with Muhammad Shreck?
你以为能和拳王许瑞克打上15回合吗?
I guess we'll find out.
看来得拭目以待
Of course, I don't have a crime boss like Cobblepot in my corner.
当然,我没有卡伯波特 那种犯罪集团首领的支持
'"Crime boss?'" Shows what you know...
"犯罪集团首领?" 证明你知道什么...
...'"Mr. To-The-Manor-Born- With-A-Silver-Spoon.'"
..."天之骄子先生"
Oswald is Gotham's new golden boy.
奥兹瓦是加森市的新英雄
If his parents hadn't 86'ed him, you'd have been bunkies at prep school.
他父母若未嫌弃他 你们俩或许会是同学室友
He controls the Red Triangle Gang. I can't prove it yet, but we both--
奥兹瓦控制红三角帮 我还无法证明,但我们俩--
I'll not stand for mud-slinging here.
韦恩,我不允许办公室内有揭人隐私之举
If my assistant was here, she'd have already escorted you out--
我的助理若在此 早已护送你出去--
Anywhere he wants.
到任何他想去的地方
Preferably some nightspot grotto...
可能是夜总会、洞穴...
...or...
...或者...
...secluded hideaway.
...隐密的藏身处
Nice suit.
好西装 谢谢
That's my name, don't wear it out or I'll make you buy me a new one.
瑟琳娜,瑟琳娜　那是我的名字,百万麦斯 别念太多而磨损,否则我要你买个新的赔我
This is Bruce...
瑟琳娜 这是布鲁斯...
...Wayne.
...韦恩
We've met.
是,我们见过
Have we?
有吗?
No, I'm sorry. I mistook me for somebody else.
噢,抱歉,我误以为自己是别人
You mean, '"mistook me.'"
你意思是--"误认我"
Isn't that what I said?
我误以为我... 对,我不是那么说的吗?
I don't think so.
不,我想不是
What happened?
怎么回事?
Did you hurt yourself...on that ski slope?
在滑雪坡上受伤了吗?
Is that why you cut short your vacation? Came back?
因此才缩短假期回来?
It's a blur.
很模糊
Not complete amnesia. I remember Sister Mary Margaret puking in church...
我是说,未完全失去记忆 我记得玛丽.玛格丽特修女在教堂呕吐...
...and Betsy saying it was morning sickness.
...而贝西.莱利说那是害喜
And the time I forgot to wear my underpants to school...
我也记得有次上学,忘了穿内裤...
...and the name of the boy who noticed was Ricky Friedburg.
...而注意到的男孩,名叫瑞奇.佛莱伯格
He's dead now.
他已经死了
But last night...
但昨晚...
...complete blur.
...完全模糊
Couldn't you just die?
很不可思议吧?
Please...
瑟琳娜,拜托...
...show out Mr. Wayne.
...送韦恩先生出去
With pleasure.
乐意之至
Your coat, Mr. Wayne.
你的外套,韦恩先生
You don't seem like the type who does business with Shreck.
你不像是那种和许瑞克做生意的人
No. You don't seem like the type to take orders from him.
不,你不像是那种会听命于他的人
Well, that's a...
嗯,那真是...
...Iong story.
...说来话长
I could free up some time.
我可以腾出点时间
-I'm listed. -I'm tempted.
我记下了 我很想听
I'm working.
我要工作
I'm leaving.
我要走了
You buy that blurry business?
爸,你相信她说的话吗?
Women.
女人
Nothing surprises me...
任何事我都不讶异,奇普...
...except your late mother.
...除了你过世的母亲
Who'd have thought Selina had a brain to damage?
谁会想到瑟琳娜竟有堪受毁坏的脑袋?
Bottom line?
最坏结果吗?
She tries to blackmail me, I'll drop her out of a higher window.
她企图勒索我 我将她推出更高的窗
Meantime...
此时...
...I've got badder fish to fry.
...我有更重要的事
Oswald...
奥兹瓦...
...it's Max.
...我是麦斯
You're home?
你在家吗?
How've you been?
你好吗?
Your extended family?
你众多的家人?
Good to have a family.
有家庭真好
I'd rather not be disturbed now.
我现在宁可不受打扰
Come on downstairs, Oswald. I have a surprise.
下楼,奥兹瓦 我要给你一个惊喜
I don't like surprises.
我不喜欢惊喜
Come on.
下来吧
Don't peek.
别偷看
You'll spoil it.
你会破坏惊喜的
Adulation is a cross to bear. God knows I know.
是的,奉受是个重担 我很清楚
But someone's got to supplant our standing in the way of progress, Mayor.
但在进步的道路上 有人必须被取代的,市长
And don't deny it, Mr. Cobblepot, you've got the magic.
别否认,卡伯波特先生 你有那种魔力
Your charisma's bigger than both of us. Come on down.
你的非凡魅力远胜过我们 下来吧
Mayor?
市长?
Mayor.
市长
Elections happen in November. It's late December.
麦斯,十一月才选举 现在是十二月底耶
Don't worry.
不用担心
I want you to meet Jen and Josh, my image consultants.
我要你见见珍和乔希-- 我的形象顾问
Here.
来
Reclaim your birthright.
拾回你天生的权利
I'm Jen.
我是珍,嗨
Okay, let's see. What I'd like to do first is put these gloves on you.
好,我看看,首先我要做的是 将这些小手套戴在你手上
Our research tells us that voters like fingers.
我们的研究显示 我们的选民喜欢手指
So if we were to just lose this....
因此,若将它藏起来,我们...
We'll do it another time.
我们改天再戴好了
Not a lot of reflective surfaces in the sewer, huh?
下水道没多少能反光的平面,对吧?
Still, it could be worse.
不过,有可能更糟
My nose could be gushing blood.
我的鼻子可能血流不止
What do you mean by that?
你的鼻子可能... 你的意思是说...?
Everybody, back to work!
所有人回去工作!
Let's make...
让我们造就...
...a mayor!
...一位市长!
You're right, we missed the regular election...
你说得对,我们错过正常排定的选举...
...but elected officials can be recalled, impeached...
...但当选官员可以改选,弹劾...
...given the boot. Look at Nixon, Agnew.
...罢黜.像尼克松,艾格纽
Then think of you...
再想想你...
...Oswald Cobblepot, filling the void.
...奥兹瓦.卡伯波特填补其位
I'd like to fill her void.
我倒想填补她
We'll need signatures to overturn the ballot. I can supply those.
我们需要签名,以促成改选 那些我能供应,奥兹瓦
-Teach her my French flipper trick. -We need one more thing.
教她我的法国鳍把戏 奥兹瓦,我们还需要一样东西
A platform?
一块踏板吗?
Stop global warming. Start global cooling. Make the world an icebox.
停止环球温室效应,开始环球冷却效应 使世界成为巨大的冰箱
I like it. But to get the mayor recalled, we must have a catalyst.
我喜欢,但要改选市长 需要一个触媒,导火线
'"You're doing great, Mayor Cobblepot.'"
"你做得很好,卡伯波特市长"
'"Your table is ready, Mayor Cobblepot.'"
"你的餐桌准备好了,卡伯波特市长"
'"l need you, Oswald. I need you now! '"
"我需要你,奥兹瓦,我现在就需要你!"
'"That's the biggest parasol I've ever seen.'"
"那是我见过最大的伞"
Soon an incident like the Gulf of Tonkin, or the Reichstag fire....
很快就会发生东京湾意外 或雷斯塔格大火...
You want my old friends up there...
你要我在上面的老朋友...
...to drive the mayor into a foaming frenzy?
...使市长发狂吗?
-Exactly. -Sounds fun.
正是 听来很好玩
But...
但是...
...I mustn't get sidetracked, Maxie.
...我不能分神,麦斯
I have my own things to tend to.
我有我的正事要办
'"Sidetracked?'" This is your chance to fulfill your destiny...
"想转移话题吗?" 奥兹瓦 打从你父母草率抛弃你到现在...
...that your parents carelessly discarded.
...这是你达成天命的机会
Reclaim my birthright, you mean?
你是指重拾我天生的权利?
Imagine, as mayor, you have the ear of the media...
试想身为市长后 你将得到媒体的注意...
...access to the captains of industry...
...企业大亨将尊重你的意见...
...unlimited poontang.
...无限制的嬉闹
You drive a hard bargain, Maxie.
你的条件很诱人,麦斯
All right, I'll be mayor.
好吧,我就当市长
Burn, baby, burn!
烧吧,宝贝,烧吧!
-Who is she? -What is she?
她是谁? 她是什么?
I don't know whether to open fire or fall in love.
我不知道是要开火 还是坠入爱河
You poor guys.
可怜的家伙
Always confusing your pistols with your privates.
手枪和私处老是搞不清楚
Don't hurt us. Our take-home's less than $300.
别伤害我们,小姐 我们的薪水不到三百块
You're overpaid. Hit the road.
薪水太高了,滚吧
Go ahead and hit me.
尽管打我吧
Admiring your handiwork?
欣赏你的作品吗?
Touring the riot scene.
参观暴乱的场面
Gravely assessing the devastation.
沉重地评估破坏情况
'"Upstanding-Mayor'" stuff.
尽"荣耀市长"的职责
You're not the mayor.
你不是市长
Things change.
世事多变
What do you want?
你有何企图?
The direct approach.
多直接的方法啊
I admire that in a man with a mask.
我欣赏一个戴面具的人能如此
You don't really think you'll win, do you?
你不会真的以为你会赢吧?
Things change.
世事多变
I saw her first. Got to fly.
我先看到她的,得走了
How could you? I'm a woman!
你怎能如此?我是个女人!
I'm sorry.
对不起,我...
As I was saying, I'm a woman and can't be taken for granted.
如我所说,我是个女人 不能让人视为理所当然
Life's a bitch, now so am l.
人生无常,我也是
Who are you?
你是谁?
Who's the man behind the bat?
蝙蝠背后是什么人?
Maybe you can help me find...
也许你能帮我找出...
...the woman...
...在猫背后的...
...behind the cat.
...女人
No, that's not you.
不,那不是你
There you are.
这才是你
Saved by Kitty Litter.
被猫担架救了一条命
Bastard!
混蛋!
Alfred...
阿佛瑞德...
...bring me some antiseptic ointment.
...帮我拿消毒软膏来,好吗?
Coming. Are you in pain, sir?
来了,会痛吗,主人?
Not really.
不太会
I may have saved the mayor's baby...
我或许救了市长的宝宝...
...but I refuse to save a mayor...
...但我拒绝救如婴儿般...
...who stood by, helpless as a baby...
...束手无策的市长...
...while Gotham was ravaged by a disease...
...使加森市遭到破坏...
...that turned Eagle Scouts into crazed clowns...
...使老鹰童子军变成疯狂小丑...
...and happy homemakers into catwomen.
...快乐的主妇变成猫女
Thank you.
谢谢
Oswald Cobblepot, the mystery man-beast, made his bid to run Gotham.
奥兹瓦.卡伯波特-- 神秘的人兽企图经营加森市
Mr. Cobblepot, you are the coolest role model a young person could have.
卡伯波特先生,你是年轻人的最佳模范
And you're the hottest young person...
是模范能得到的...
...a role model could have.
...最热情的年轻人
Here.
来
Wear a button.
戴个徽章
Let me just get it on here.
让我帮戴在这里
Thank you.
谢谢大家
This mayor stuff is not about power, it's about reaching out to people...
我真的会喜欢候选市长这种事 非关权力,而是接触人民...
...touching people, groping people.
...触摸人民,抚摸人民
-Penguin-- -My name is not Penguin!
企鹅-- 我不叫企鹅!
It's Oswald Cobblepot.
我是奥兹瓦.卡伯波特
Oswald, there's somebody here to see you.
奥兹瓦,有人要见你
Just the pussy I've been looking for.
正是我在找的女人
It's chilly in here.
这里真冷
I'll warm you.
我会使温暖
Down, Oswald.
冷静,奥兹瓦
We need to talk.
我们需要谈谈
You see...
你瞧...
...you and I have something in common.
...你和我有共通之处
Sounds familiar.
听来很熟悉
Appetite for destruction?
毁灭的僻好?
Contempt for the czars of fashion?
对流行大师的鄙视?
Wait, don't tell me.
等等,别告诉我
Naked sexual charisma?
赤裸裸的性魅力?
Batman.
蝙蝠侠
The thorn in both our sides.
我们的共同仇敌
The fly in our ointment.
药膏中的苍蝇
Ointment?
药膏?
I've got scented and unscented.
我有有气味的和无气味的
I'll come back later.
我会再回来
Perchance, are you a registered voter? I'm a mayoral prospect.
对了,是登记投票人吗? 我是市长候选人
I have but one pet cause today!.
我今天来只有一个目的--
Ban the Bat.
打倒蝙蝠
Oh, him again. No bother. He's already history. Check it out.
噢,又是他,没问题 他已经完了,看
We'll disassemble his Batmobile and turn it into an H-bomb on wheels.
我们要拆开他的蝙蝠车 将它变成活动氢弹
He'd have even more power as a martyr.
不,不 他的力量比殉道者还大
To destroy Batman, we must first turn him into what he hates the most.
要消灭蝙蝠侠 首先得将他变成他最痛恨的人
Namely, us.
那就是--我们
Frame him?
是指陷害他?
Not even in office yet and already an enemies list.
还没上任就有黑名单了
Those names are not for prying eyes.
那些名字不能任人窥探
Why shouid i trust some catbroad anyway?
我为何要信任一个猫女?
Maybe you're a screwed-up sorority chick getting back at her daddy...
也许只是个心理不平衡的名媛 想报复父亲...
...for not buying her that pony when she turned sweet-sixteen.
...只因她年满16岁时,没帮她买匹小马
Nice birdie.
好鸟
Nice kitty.
好猫
Batman napaimed my arm.
蝙蝠侠伤了我的手臂
He knocked me off a buiiding just when i started to feei good about myseif.
在我才开始满意自己时 就害我跌落谷底
i want to piay an integrai part in his degradation.
我要在他坠落时 扮演重要角色
A pian is forming.
计划正在形成
i want in.
我要参加
The thought of busting Batman makes me feei aii...
想到要害蝙蝠侠 就令我觉得...
...dirty.
...肮脏
Maybe i'ii just give myseif a bath right here.
或许我就在这儿,给自己洗个澡
I challenge the mayor...
我质疑市长...
...to re-light the Christmas tree in Gotham Plaza tomorrow night.
...明晚在加森广场要重新点燃圣诞树
Sir, shaii we change the channei to a program with some dignity and ciass?
主人,我们该不该换个频道,看些高级节目呢?
The Love Connection perhaps?
爱的联机怎么样?
...not that I have any faith in the mayor.
...不是我对市长没信心
But I hope and pray...
但我希望和祈祷...
...that Batman...
...蝙蝠侠...
...will be present to preserve the peace.
...能在场并维护和平
Subtie.
不可思议
Why are you doing this?
为何你要这样做?
Seiina?
瑟琳娜?
Sorry, i didn't mean to scare you.
抱歉,我不是想吓
Scare me? i was just scaring myseif.
吓我?我是自己吓到而已
i don't see how, but....
我不知道为何,但...
it's nice to see you in the reai worid, away from Shreck.
很高兴在远离许瑞克的真实世界中见到
it's nice to be here.
很高兴是在这里
Are you aii right?
没事吧?
You iook iike you have the hoiiday biues or something.
看起来有点忧郁或者有心事
Boy, the news these days.
帅哥,这几天的新闻
Weird!
怪怪的!
i heard on TV that Catwoman weighs 140 pounds.
我听电视上说"猫女重140磅"
How do these hacks sieep at night?
这些人晚上睡饱了没事干?
it's not even accurate. "Batman biows it""?
那还更扯,居然说"蝙蝠侠炸的"?
He probabiy saved miiiions in property damage aione.
他很可能独自救了百万人的生命财产
You're not going to the re-iighting of the tree, are you?
你不是要去参加重燃圣诞树典礼吗?
i wouidn't be caught dead there.
我才不要自找没趣哩
it's going to be a hot time in the coid town tonight.
那可是今晚这寒冷城镇最热闹的时刻
You got kind of a dark side, don't you?
属于黑暗一类的,不是吗?
No darker than yours.
没有比你更黑暗的了
Why don't you come over and we can watch it on TV?
何不来我那儿,一起在电视前看?
The tree-iighting ceremony.
圣诞树点亮典礼
i can't. i have to be somewhere tonight.
不行,我今晚还有别处要去
How about coming for dinner at five?
下午五点来我家晚餐,如何?
Let's say six?
或者六点如何?
Five.
好的,五点
Five. You and me.
就五点,和我
The tree iights up and then i push the button.
圣诞树一亮,然后我按钮
Wait, wait.
等等,等等
i push the button, then the tree iights up.
我按钮,然后圣诞树就亮了
Who are you?
你是谁?
Taient scout.
星探
Come in.
请进
i don't just iight trees. i'm an actress as weii.
你知道我不但会点亮圣诞树 我还是个女演员
What is that thing? A camera or something?
那是什么东西? 照像机还是什么?
Say, '"Cheese! '"
这叫"好东西!"
Cheese.
好东西
Thanks, Aifred.
谢谢你,阿佛瑞德
i'm sure he's wonderfui company...
我确信他是个好同伴...
...but doesn't the '"goid-piated-bacheior'" bit get a iittie staie?
...但"富有单身汉"不觉得无聊吗?
A iot iike the '"ioneiy-secretary'" syndrome, i guess.
我猜和"寂寞秘书"一样
Executive Assistant.
执行助理
Sorry.
抱歉
Secretary.
秘书
Any girifriend?
有女朋友吗?
Sure.
当然
You mean, as in serious?
噢,你是说...认真的?
No. Had one, didn't work.
不,有过一个,没再交往了
What went wrong? Hang on!
出了什么差错? 慢着!
i think i know!
我想我知道!
You kept things from her.
你有事瞒着她
i toid her everything.
不,我将一切都告诉她
The truth frightened her?
而那个事实吓到了她?
There are two truths...
有两个事实...
...you know?
...知道吗?
She had troubie reconciiing them because i had troubie...
她无法调和二者 因为我也无法...
...reconciiing them.
...调和二者 是
Vicki thought--
所以,维基认为--
Vicki?
维基?
ice skater or stewardess?
溜冰好手或空姐?
No, she was a photojournaiist.
不,她是个摄影记者
Was Vicki right about your...
那对你双重性的困扰...
...difficuity with duaiity?
...维基的看法对吗?
You see...
知道的...
...if i say yes, then...
...我若说是,那...
...you'ii think of me as a...
...会以为我是个...
...Norman Bates, a Ted Bundy type and....
...像泰德.邦迪的杀人狂,而且...
You might not iet me kiss you.
也许不肯让我吻
it's the so-caiied normai guys who aiways iet you down.
会令人失望的 一向是所谓的正常人
Sickos never scare me. At ieast they're committed.
狂人从未吓到我 至少他们执着
i can't do that.
我不能那么做
Neither can i.
我也不能
This is a special bulletin. The Ice Princess has been kidnapped.
这是特别报导 冰雪公主被绑架了
Can you confirm reports of Batman's suspected involvement in the abduction?
戈登署长,你能证实 蝙蝠侠涉嫌绑架的传闻吗?
The evidence is purely circumstantial.
这个证据纯粹是间接的
This was found, stained with blood, in the missing girl's dressing room.
它沾了血迹 是在失踪女孩的更衣室找到的
-i must go. -No, it's your house.
我得走了 不,是我,这是你家
Hoid on. Just sit for a second and reiax. i'ii be right back.
慢着,坐一下,轻松点 我马上回来
i've got to go to the piaza.
阿佛瑞德,我得到广场去 我看到了
-He is begging me to show. -i hoped you'd snub him.
是,我知道,他正乞求我出现 我希望你别理他,好吗?
i can't. There's been a kidnapping. Here's what i want you to do.
不行,那是绑架案 听着,我要你这么做
Shit!
糟糕!
Teii Seiina, Ms. Kyie, i had to go out of town.
告诉瑟琳娜,也就是凯尔小姐 告诉她...我得进城去
Teii her that a big business deai came up.... You know what?
告诉她...我突然有笔大生意要处理 不,你知道吧?告诉她...
Let her know, not in some kind of dumb, '"be-my-girifriend'" way--
让她知道,不是用愚蠢的 "做我女友"的方法--
i'ii reiay the message.
我会转达讯息的 太好了
Mr. Wayne toid me to teii you that--
凯尔小姐　阿佛瑞德 韦恩先生叫我告诉--
Bruce, yes....
韦恩先生? 布鲁斯,对...
Wouid you teii him...
可否代我告诉他...
...i've been going through... a iot of changes and....
...我历经许多... 改变....
Just that...
不,只要告诉他...
...this is not a rejection...
...我的突然离去...
...my abruptiy ieaving.
...并非拒绝
in fact, he makes me feei the way...
事实上,他使我觉得有...
...i hope i reaiiy am.
...我真正希望拥有的感受
Couid you just make up a sonnet or... a dirty iimerick?
不!你能编个借口或是... 找个理由吗?
One has just sprung to mind.
我正好想到一个
This way, ma'am.
谢谢 这边,小姐　抱歉
Ladies and Gentlemen.
女士、先生们
Please, may I have your attention?
请注意一下好吗?
I know that to many of you...
我知道对许多人而言...
...Gotham seems a bit beleaguered these days.
...近来加森市似乎灾祸不断
But I want you to know your elected officials...
但我要你们知道 你们选的官员...
...and your police department...
...和警方...
...have the situation well in hand.
...已经控制住情势
Got to hurry.
要快点
Thank you.
谢谢你
it was set up to iook iike i did it.
这是陷阱,好让人觉得是我做的
i'ii teii the poiice i was kidnapped by an ugiy birdman with fish breath.
别担心,我会告诉警方 我是被一个有鱼腥味的丑鸟人所绑架
Did somebody say fish?
有人提到鱼吗?
i haven't been fed aii day.
我整天都未进食哩!
Eat fioor.
吃地板吧
High fiber.
高纤
Hey, stud...
嘿,帅哥...
-...i thought we had something together. -We do.
...我以为我们互相吸引 没错
Got to go. Giri taik.
得走了 女孩说的
She iet me go. i think 'cause i reasoned with her, giri-to-giri.
她放我走了 我想是因为我以女孩立场跟她讲理
Be carefui. Don't move.
小心,别动
Lawn dart!
草地飞镖!
Rats with wings, do your thing.
有翅膀的老鼠,做拿手的事吧
Batman pushed the Princess!
蝙蝠侠推落冰雪公主!
Hoid your fire!
停火!
You're catnip to a giri iike me.
你对我这种女孩,很有吸引力
Handsome, dazed...
英俊,迷人...
...and to die for.
...值得付出一切代价
Mistietoe can be deadiy if you eat it.
若吃w寄生会致命
But a kiss...
但你若认真...
...can be even deadiier if you mean it.
...一个吻会更致命
You're the second man who's kiiied me this week.
你是这礼拜第二个杀我的人
But i've got seven iives ieft.
但我还剩七条命
i tried to save you--
我试过救--
Seems iike every woman you try to save ends up dead.
似乎你企图救的女人 结果都死了
Or deepiy resentfui.
或大为责怪你
Maybe you shouid retire.
也许你该退休了
Damn.
可恶
Outstanding!
真出色!
You're Beauty and the Beast...
是美女与野兽...
...in one iuscious Christmas gift pack.
...以性感包装的圣诞礼物
You said you'd scare the ice Princess.
你说你只要吓吓冰雪公主
She iooked pretty scared to me.
她看来蛮怕我的
A touch of the bubbiy?
来点香槟?
So what are we waiting for?
那么,我们还在等什么?
Let's consummate our fiendish union.
让我们结合圆房吧
What?
你在说些什么?
Oh, come on.
噢,别这样
Can't you picture?
无法想象吗?
it's dark in the mayor's mansion.
市长的华宅一片黑暗
i'm bushed, so here you come into the bedroom...
我精疲力尽,于是进卧室...
...twitching your iittie taii...
...扭着的小尾巴...
...my siippers in one hand, a dry martini in the other.
...一手拿我的拖鞋 一手拿杯纯马丁尼
Piease.
多棒啊
i wouidn't touch you to scratch you.
我无论如何都不会碰你
You iousy minx! i shouid have you spayed! You sent out aii the signais!
这差劲的妞儿!我该阉掉的! 少在那儿装模作样!
i don't think i iike you anymore!
我想我不再喜欢了!
Good-bye, my unintended.
再见,我无缘的人
Go to heaven.
上天堂吧
There he is!
他在那里!
Don't adjust your sets.
别调整屏幕
Welcome...
欢迎光临...
...to the Oswald Cobblepot School of Driving.
...奥兹瓦.卡伯波特驾驶学校
Gentlemen, start your screaming.
各位先生,开始尖叫吧
This may be a bad time to mention it, but my license has expired!
也许此时提起,时机不对 但我的驾照过期了!
Relax.
轻松点
I'll take care of the squealing, wretched, pinhead puppets of Gotham!
我会对付加森市那些 尖叫的、可怜的白痴市民!
You must admit I played this stinking city like a harp from hell!
你必须承认 我玩弄这个臭城市于股掌之间!
Heipiess oid iady at 12:00 high!
十二点方向,有个无助的老太太!
That's funny.
真有趣
Now i'm a iittie worried.
现在我有点担心了
So he survived. Why worry?
就算他活着,有什么好担心?
He didn't even iose a iimb! An eyebaii! Biadder controi!
他毫发无伤! 眼珠子!失禁!都没有!
Listen to them. They've iost faith in oid symbois.
重点是听听他们 他们对旧象征已失去信心
They're ready to bond with you, the icon of the future.
他们已认同你是未来的代表
if it works, don't fix it.
若是成功,就别再改变
We'ii ceiebrate tonight at my annuai baii.
我们今晚在我的周年舞会上庆祝
Shreck and Cobbiepot...
许瑞克和卡伯波特...
...the visionary aiiiance.
...耀眼的联盟 走吧
When it came time...
在维护我们这个...
...to ensure the safety of our fair city...
...美丽城市的时刻...
...did the mayor have a plan?
...市长有计划吗?
No!
没有!
He relied on a man.
他依赖一个人
A Batman.
一个蝙蝠侠
A ticking time-bomb of a costumed freak....
一个服装怪异的定时炸弹....
Our prime concern is this ghastiy grotesque.
我们主要关切的是这个可怕的怪物
But iet's not forget about repairing the Batmobiie.
但也别忘了修蝙蝠车
There's security to consider.
得考虑安全问题
We can't just take it to any oid body shop.
我们不能将它任意送到一个修车厂
Security?
安全问题?
Who iet Vicki Vaie into the Batcave?
谁让维基.维尔进蝙蝠洞?
i'm working, i turn around and there she is. '"Hi, Vick. Come on in.'"
我正在工作,一转身,她便在那里 "嗨,维基,请进"
-Ready? -i'ii take the stairs.
准备好了吗? 我想我走楼梯
You ask...am I up here for personal glory?
你们问我...我是否为个人荣耀上场?
No.
不是
The glory that I yearn to recapture...
我渴望重拾的荣耀...
...is the glory of Gotham!
...是加森市的荣耀!
How can this be accomplished?
我要如何达成?
I know...
我知道...
...you're all concerned.
...你们都很关心
Relax.
轻松点
I'll take care of the squealing, wretched, pinhead puppets of Gotham.
我会对付加森市那些 尖叫的、可怜的白痴市民
i didn't say that.
我没有那么说
You must admit I played this stinking city...
你必须承认 我玩弄这个臭城市...
...Iike a harp from hell!
...于股掌之间! 嘿......
You must admit...
你必须承认...
...I played this stinking city like a harp from hell!
...我玩弄这个臭城市于股掌之间! 嘿......
Why is there aiways someone who brings eggs and tomatoes to a speech?
为什么总有人带着蛋和蕃茄参加演说?
There he is!
他在那里!
My babies.
我的宝贝们
Did you miss me?
你们想我吗?
Great speech, Oswaid.
很棒的演说,奥兹瓦
My name is not Oswaid!
我不叫奥兹瓦!
it's Penguin!
是企鹅!
i am not a human being!
我不是人类!
i am an animai. Coid-biooded!
我是个冷血动物!
Crank the A.C.!
空调加强点!
Where are my iists? Bring me the names!
我的名单呢?将名字送上来!
it's time.
时候到了
These are the names of the first-born sons of Gotham City.
这些是加森市长子们的名字
Just iike i was.
就和我一样
And iike me, a terribie fate waits for them.
而和我一样,可怕的命运在等着他们
Tonight, whiie their parents party...
今晚,当他们的父母狂欢时...
...they'ii be dreaming away...
...他们将作梦...
...in their safe cribs...
...在他们的摇篮...
...their soft beds...
...在他们的软床...
...and we'ii snatch them...
...而我们将劫走他们...
...carry them into the sewer...
...带他们到下水道...
...and toss them into a deep, dark, watery grave.
...将他们丢进深黑的水底坟墓
Penguin?
企鹅?
Kiiiing sieeping chiidren...
杀死熟睡儿童...
...isn't that a iittie....
...岂不是有一点...
No, it's a iot.
不,是很多
A reminder.
韦恩先生,提醒你
Tonight is that ioathsome party hosted by the odious Mr. Shreck.
今晚那个可恶的许瑞克先生 要举办讨厌的派对
May we RSVP in the resoundingiy negative?
我们能严正回绝吗?
Not interested.
没兴趣
Aithough...
不过...
...Seiina Kyie might be there.
...瑟琳娜.凯尔可能会在场
ingenious costume.
真出色的服装
Let me guess.
我来猜猜看
Trust-fund goody-goody?
基金会的好人?
Feeiing good?
感觉很好吧?
You aimost made a monster the mayor of Gotham City.
你差点使一个怪物当上加森市长
i am the iight of this city...
我是本市之光...
...and i am its mean, twisted soui.
...我是它卑劣、疯狂的灵魂
Does it matter who's mayor?
谁当市长有关系吗?
it does to me.
对我而言是的
Yawn.
无聊
i'm sorry about yesterday, but i had...
听着,昨天很抱歉,我得...
...a pretty big deai come through. Faii through, actuaiiy.
...去处理一大笔生意
it's okay. i had to go home and feed my cat.
没关系 我得回家去喂我的猫
No hard feeiings then?
那不伤感情?
Actuaiiy...
事实上...
...semi-hard, i'd say.
...应该是半伤
There's a big, comfy Caiifornia King over in Bedding.
寝具部有个大而舒适的双人床
Why don't we....
我们何不....
Take off our costumes?
脱掉舞会服装吗?
i'm tired of wearing masks.
我已厌倦戴面具了
Me too.
我也是
Let me ask you something.
让我问一件事
Why'd you come tonight?
今晚为何而来?
-You first. -To see you.
你先说 来看
Loveiy.
说得真好
i wish i couid say the same, but i came for Max.
但愿我能说同样的话 但我是为了麦斯来的
Do you mean you....
的意思是....
Not you and Max?
该不会和麦斯?
Me and Max?
哈......我和麦斯?
No. This and Max.
不,这个和麦斯
Don't teii me kiiiing Max won't soive anything, because it wiii.
不,别告诉我杀死麦斯无法解决一切 因为那一定会的
Aren't you tired of this sanctimonious robber baron...
你不厌倦这虚伪的强盗大亨...
...coming out on top when he shouid be six feet under?
...总是获胜 他不该被埋在六找韵侣?
You may have probiems with your boss, but who do you think you are?
或许和老板之间有很多问题 但以为是谁啊?
i don't know anymore, Bruce.
我已经不知道了,布鲁斯
A kiss under the mistietoe.
w寄生下的吻
'"Mistietoe can be deadiy if you eat it.'"
"若吃w寄生会致命"
'"But a kiss can be even deadiier...
"但你若认真..."
'"...if you mean it.'"
"...一个吻会更致命"
Oh, my God.
噢,我的天
Does this mean we have to start fighting?
这是否意味我们得开始打斗?
Let's go outside.
我们到外面去
-Are you okay? -i'm aii right.
爸　儿子 你没事吧?　我很好
You didn't invite me...
你们没邀请我...
...so i crashed!
...所以我不请自来!
What do you want?
你要做什么?
Right now, my troops...
现在,我的部队...
...are fanning out across town...
...正在全城搜寻...
...for your chiidren!
...你们的孩子!
Yes!
没错!
For your first-born sons!
是你们的长子!
The ones you ieft defenseiess at home...
你们使他无助在家...
...so you couid dress up iike jerks...
...好让自己能打扮得像傻瓜...
...get juiced and dance...
...喝着果汁和跳舞...
...badiy!
...坏透了!
i've personaiiy come...
我亲自前来...
...for Gotham's favorite son...
...为抓加森市最喜爱的儿子...
...Mr. Chip Shreck.
...奇普.许瑞克先生
You're coming with me, you Great White Dope...
跟我走,你这个大白痴...
...to die, way down in the sewer!
...以便死在下面的下水道中!
Not Chip. if you have any human feeiing, take me instead.
别抓奇普 你若有丝毫人,就抓我代替吧
i don't. So, no!
我没有,因此,不行!
i'm the one you want.
我才是你要的
isn't it Max Shreck who manipuiated and betrayed you?
操纵和背叛你的,不是麦斯.许克吗?
isn't it Max, not Chip...
你要看到他在下水道中淹死的...
...you want to see immersed to his eyebaiis in raw sewage?
...不就是麦斯,而非奇普吗?
Okay, you got a point.
好吧,你说的有理
i'ii iet the iittie prince iive, for now.
我就暂时让这小子活着
in the duck!
进鸭子里去!
This is going to be good...
实在太好了...
...to cut down a whoie crop of Gotham's most promising...
...在加森市最有希望的作物成熟前...
...before their prime.
...将它们砍断
You ask me...how do i iure them in?
你是在问我...如何引诱他们?
A iittie '"Pied Penguin'" action.
一点"杂耍企鹅"把戏
And you get to watch them sink...
你可以看着他们沈入...
...into a deep puddie...
...一大池...
...of your industriai by-products.
...你的工业副产品中
Then...
然后...
...you join them.
...你再加入他们
Hurry up and get those kids ioaded.
快点将那些孩子装好,好吗?
Right this way, kiddies.
这边走,孩子们
Come with me.
跟我走
So where are aii the chiidren?
所有小孩在哪呢?
'"Dear Penguin:
"亲爱的企鹅:"
'"The chiidren regret they're unabie to attend.
"小孩们懊悔不克参加"
'"Batman! '"
"蝙蝠侠!"
My dear penguins...
我亲爱的企鹅们...
...we stand on a great threshoid!
...我们站在一个大关键点上!
it's okay to be scared!
害怕是正常的!
Many of you won't be coming back.
你们有许多人将回不来
Thanks to Batman...
多谢蝙蝠侠...
...the time has come...
...惩罚所有神的子民的时刻...
...to punish aii God's chiidren!
...来临了!
First-, second-, third- and fourth-born!
长子,次子,三子和四子!
Why be biased?
为何要有偏见?
Maie and femaie!
男的和女的!
Heii, the sexes are equai...
妈的,男女平等...
...with their erogenous zones...
...将他们的性感带...
...biown sky-high!
...炸向高空!
Forward...
向前走...
...march!
...前进!
The iiberation of Gotham...
解放加森市...
...has begun!
...已经开始!
The penguins are moving above ground.
企鹅们在地面上活动了
Penguin army...
企鹅部队...
...approaching launch destination at Gotham Plaza.
...接近发射目的地--加森广场
One minute until ignition.
距发射一分钟
They wouidn't put me on a pedestai...
他们不尊重我...
...so i'm iaying them on a siab!
...我就让他们送命!
Penguins seem to be converging on Gotham Plaza.
企鹅似乎在加森广场集结
Thirty seconds until ignition.
距发射三十秒
Estimated casualties after launch:
发射后估计死亡人数:
100,000 people.
十万人
The penguins have reached Gotham Square.
企鹅们已抵达加森广场
Fifteen seconds to ignition.
距发射十五秒
Ready when you are, sir.
准备好了,主人
10-,9-,8-,7- i've got the coordinates.
我已定好坐标
Let's turn them around.
好了,让他们转向 是,主人
Something is wrong.
情况不对
Something has jammed the signal.
讯号被干扰了
They seem to be turning around.
他们似乎转向了
There is also something coming this way.
过来 还有某种东西往这边来了
Very large. Very fast.
非常大,非常快
Who's there?
谁在那里?
i'm homing in on the signai's origin.
我进入讯号中心了
You're jeaious because i'm a genuine freak...
你嫉妒我是个纯种怪物...
...and you have to wear a mask!
...而你得戴着面具!
You might be right.
也许你说得对
But what it aii comes down to is: Who's hoiding the umbreiia?
但最重要的是: 谁拿着雨伞?
My babies!
我的宝贝啊!
i don't know what you want, but i can get it with a minimum of fuss.
我不知道想要什么 但只要我花一点功夫,就能弄到...
Money.
金钱...
Jeweis.
珠宝
A very big baii of string.
很大一串的珠宝
Your biood, Max.
你的血,麦斯 我的血?
i gave at the office.
我在办公室捐过了
A haif-pint. i'm taiking gaiions.
只有半品脱,我要的是半加仑
Let's make a deai!
我们来谈条件!
Other than my biood, what can i do?
除了我的血,我能为做什么?
Sorry, Max. A die for a die.
抱歉,麦斯,以死还死
You're not just saving a iife--
你不只在救一条命--
Shut up. You're going to jaii.
也是在救... 闭嘴,你要去坐牢了
Don't be naive. The iaw doesn't appiy to peopie iike him...or us.
别天真了 法律对像他这样的人...或我们,都莫可奈何
Wrong on both counts.
二者皆非
Why do this?
为何要如此做?
Let's just take him to the poiice.
我们将他交给警方
Then we can go home...
然后我们可以...
...together.
...一起回家
Seiina...
瑟琳娜...
...don't you see?
...不懂吗?
We're the same.
我们是一样的
Spiit...
由中间...
...down the center.
...分裂为二
Piease.
瑟琳娜,拜托
Bruce...
布鲁斯...
...i wouid iove to iive with you in your castie...
...我愿意和你住在你的城堡中...
...forever, just iike in a fairy taie.
...直到永远,一如童话故事
i just couidn't iive with myseif. Don't pretend this is a happy ending.
我就是无法忍受我自己 别假装这是个快乐结局
Seiina Kyie.
瑟琳娜 瑟琳娜.凯尔
You're fired.
被开除了
And Bruce Wayne...
还有布鲁斯.韦恩...
...why are you dressed up iike Batman?
...你为何作蝙蝠侠的装扮?
Because he is Batman, you moron!
因为他是蝙蝠侠,低能的家伙!
Was.
以前是
Don't.
不要
You kiiied me, the Penguin kiiied me, Batman kiiied me.
你杀我,企鹅杀我,蝙蝠侠杀我
Three iives down. Got enough to finish me off?
去掉三条命 你有足够的子弹解决我吗?
One way to find out.
只有一个办法能知道
Four.
四
Five.
五
Stiii aiive!
仍然活着!
Six.
六
Seven.
七
Aii good giris go to heaven.
好女孩都上天堂
Two iives ieft.
还剩两条命
i'ii save one for next Christmas.
我想该留下一条,过明年的圣诞节
But in the meantime...
但在这同时...
...how about a kiss, Santie Ciaus?
...吻一下,如何,圣诞老人?
Shit!
可恶!
i picked a cute one.
选到一把可爱的
The heat's getting to me.
热气使我不舒服
i'ii murder you momentariiy.
我马上就误杀你
But first...
但首先...
...i need a cooi drink...
...我需要喝...
...of ice water.
...冰水
Stop the car.
停车
Come what may...
无论如何...
...Merry Christmas, Mr. Wayne.
...圣诞快乐,韦恩先生
Merry Christmas, Aifred.
圣诞快乐,阿佛瑞德
Goodwiii toward men.
平安归于男人
And women.
和女人